{"tossups": [{"question": "One character in this story says that he would \u201cas soon put fire-works in [a] pillow-case\" as invite Henry and Julia to his house. A \u201cweek of fog and rain\u201d worsens the smell emanating from the title object of this story. That object is described as a \u201cdebased Romanesque\u201d with \u201cdelirium tremens\u201d which makes the protagonist \u201ctired to follow it.\u201d The protagonist of this story throws her key into a (*) plantain leaf, keeping her caregiver Jennie locked out of her room. That protagonist\u2019s husband, John, threatens to send her to Dr. Weir Mitchell if she does not get well soon. The protagonist of this story sees a woman in the \u201cdark grape arbors\u201d who is \u201ccreeping all around the garden.\u201d For 10 points, name this short story whose narrator goes insane seeing figures creeping around in the title object, written by Charlotte Perkins Gilman.", "answer": "\u201cThe Yellow Wallpaper\u201d", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This character dreams of a virus of nihilism ravaging the minds of Europe, as well as a woman who only laughs harder every time he hits her. He receives a cypress cross before repeatedly kissing the ground at a crossroads. This character decides to hide in an apartment inhabited by two painters when he sees a pair of strangers coming through a doorway he thought was locked. After completing his most famous action, this character decides to visit (*) Razmukhin and other acquaintances including the prostitute Sonya. This character tries to evade the questions of the detective Porfiry Petrovich regarding the murder of Alyona Ivanova, a St. Petersburg pawnbroker. For 10 points, name this protagonist of Fyodor Dostoyevsky\u2019s Crime and Punishment.", "answer": "Rodion Romanovich Raskolnikov [accept either underlined name]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This story's author earlier wrote an essay which traces this story's central theme to a discussion of atoms in Aristotle's Metaphysics. A language in this story is described as a dialect of Guarani, while a footnote in this story mentions Cavalieri and claims that Letizia Alvarez de Toledo said its title location is \u201cpointless.\u201d Closets enable people to sleep standing up in this story, whose epigraph was taken from Robert Burton\u2019s (*) The Anatomy of Melancholy. People search for Vindications, which tell people\u2019s lives, in this story, which describes Purifiers who search for the \u201cCrimson Hexagon.\u201d This story\u2019s narrator references works called Combed Thunder and The Plaster Cramp he found in its title location, which contains books with 410 pages and 40 lines arranged in an infinite number of hexagonal rooms. For 10 points, name this story by Jorge Luis Borges.", "answer": "\u201cThe Library of Babel\u201d [accept \u201cLa biblioteca de Babel\u201d]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this play asks her maid Pimple \u201chow do you like my present dress?\u201d to which he says it resembles the \u201cCherry in the Beaux Stratagem.\u201d One character in this play tries to relate his experiences fighting with the Duke of Marlborough, only to be interrupted by requests for punch. A subplot of this play concerns a character stealing a box of jewels from his mother, which nearly allows two other characters to elope. Tony (*) Lumpkin is told that he is twenty-one years old at the end of this play, which allows Constance and Hastings to marry. A woman in this play decides to act as a barmaid to overcome another character\u2019s shyness; that character mistakes the main setting for an inn. For 10 points, name this comedy in which Charles Marlow is won over by Kate Hardcastle, written by Oliver Goldsmith.", "answer": "She Stoops to Conquer", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This character presses his face against a child\u2019s and argues that nobody can truly know God\u2019s intentions in reference to that child\u2019s birth. This character plans on departing for Europe on a secret ship and is forced to live with a physician who takes the covers off of him while he sleeps; that physician is nicknamed \u201cthe leech.\" This increasingly sickly character forms an \u201celectric chain\u201d with his lover and child just before he sees a (*) meteor while confessing his sins on a scaffold. This character dies soon after giving an inspired sermon on Election Day, and exposing his infidelity is the goal of Roger Chillingworth\u2019s plotting. For 10 points, name this Boston reverend who is the father of Pearl and lover of Hester in The Scarlet Letter.", "answer": "Arthur Dimmesdale [accept either]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A sequel to this poem describes people who are \u201climping and lean and forlorn\u201d and \u201chave neither food nor money.\u201d This poem, which observes that \u201csomeone has blundered,\u201d describes a scene as \u201cshattered and sundered.\u201d This poem, a sequel to which was written by Rudyard Kipling, questions whether any of its subjects were \u201cdismayed.\u201d The (*) \u201cjaws of Death\u201d and \u201cmouth of hell\u201d engulf the subjects of this poem, which states that \u201call the world wondered\u201d about their title action. The subjects of this poem, which begins by stating \u201chalf a league\u201d three times, \u201cflashed all their sabres bare.\u201d This poem, whose title group is composed of 600 men, was inspired by an event at the Battle of Balaclava. For 10 points, name this poem based on an ill-fated Crimean War maneuver, written by Alfred, Lord Tennyson.", "answer": "\u201cThe Charge of the Light Brigade\u201d", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In one work, this man described a man who mistakenly believes he found the pituitary in a girl's foot while massaging her as well as a group of South Sea Islanders who build wooden replica airports. This man described a future with machines the size of atoms and performing operations in \"a billion tiny factories\" in \"There's Plenty of Room at the Bottom,\" inspiring the field of nanotechnology. Murray (*) Gell-Mann criticized one work by this man, the last chapter of which is adapted from a speech that this writer gave at a commencement ceremony and is titled \u201cCargo Cult Science.\u201d The title of that autobiography by this scientist, which also describes his work on the Manhattan Project and his love of bongo drumming, tells him, \u201cSurely You're Joking!\u201d For 10 points, name this scientist who co-authored a textbook based on his lectures in physics at Caltech.", "answer": "Richard Feynman [accept Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman!]"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this novel steps on an uneven stone, which reminds him of the tiles on the floor of the Baptistry of San Marco. The tailor Jupien walks into a hotel where his lover Baron de Charlus was whipped in this novel. After the protagonist of this novel smells a public toilet, he wrestles with Gilberte. The narrator of this novel believes that Andr\u00e9e is having a secret lesbian affair with (*) Albertine. A symphony written by Vinteuil serves as the love song for two characters in this novel. A character in this novel falls in love with the musician Odette de Crecy; that character, Charles Swann, titles the first section of this novel. The protagonist\u2019s memories of Combray resurface after he dips a madeleine in tea in this novel. For 10 points, name this seven-volume novel written by Marcel Proust.", "answer": "In Search of Lost Time [or Remembrance of Things Past; or A la recherche du temps perdu; anti-prompt on Time Regained, Sodom and Gomorrah, In the Shadow of Young Girls in Flower, or Swann\u2019s Way]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One poem by this author notes that \u201cI let down the crystal curtain\u201d after describing steps \u201cquite with dew.\u201d The speaker of another poem by this author claims \u201cI never laughed, being bashful\u201d after stating \u201cat fourteen, I married My Lord you.\u201d That poem later laments that \u201cmonkeys make sorrowful noise overhead.\u201d The speaker raises their cup to the title object in a poem by this author, which claims \u201cbound forever, relentless we roam\u201d after saying \u201cI (*) pour myself a drink.\u201d The speaker of one of his poems lowers his head in memory of his hometown after lifting it towards the moon. Ezra Pound translated many of this man\u2019s poems, one of which compares \u201cmoonlight before my bed\u201d to \u201cfrost on the ground.\u201d For 10 points, name this Tang dynasty poet of \u201cDrinking Alone by Moonlight\u201d and \u201cQuiet Night Thought.\u201d", "answer": "Li Bai [accept Li Bo, Li Po, Li Pai, Taibai, or Rihaku; prompt on Bai, Bo, Po, or Pai]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This character overhears his lover, a French opera dancer, commenting on his \"deformities\" after learning that she has been cheating on him with an English policeman. This character asks his love interest, \u201cWere you happy?\u201d after examining her painting of a sinking ship. After teaming up with a potential suitor for a game of charades, this character admits that he doesn\u2019t have as much money as that suitor thought while he\u2019s disguised as a (*) gypsy. This character, who is found blinded living at Ferndean, blames his servant Grace Poole for ripping a wedding veil. This character\u2019s former home, Thornfield Hall, was burned down by another woman whom the protagonist learns about on her wedding night. Bertha Mason was the first wife of, for 10 points, what eventual husband of Jane Eyre?", "answer": "Edward Fairfax Rochester", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The title character of a novel by this author leaves a note to friends in Martha\u2019s Vineyard before going to New York to meet Ramona. In another novel by this author, a character runs away from Indiana to train an eagle to eat a lizard. The protagonist of another novel by this author moves a wooden statue of Mummah and becomes the title figure of the Wariri. That character is guided by (*) Romilayu. In one novel by this author, the title character fights for custody of June with his ex-wife Madeleine, and writes letters to figures like Dwight Eisenhower. Another of this author\u2019s characters declares \u201cI am American, Chicago born\u201d before going to work for Einhorn. For 10 points, name this author of Herzog, Henderson the Rain King and The Adventures of Augie March.", "answer": "Saul Bellow", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A section from this book is about a Jewish man named Melchizidek who debates about what religion is true. In another part of this book, the Marquis de Saluzzo tells his wife that he has put her children to death before showing her that they are alive. In a third section of this book, a man marries a woman after giving her his only possession, a pet falcon, as a meal. Gotthold Lessing\u2019s play Nathan the Wise was inspired by the (*) \u201cring parable\u201d which originated in this collection. A character from this collection is the only one who can ignore the daily topic, suggesting that he represents the author. That character, Dioneo, tells the last story of each evening to characters like Fiametta and Filostrato, who are all escaping the Black Death. For 10 points, name this collection of 100 stories by Bocaccio.", "answer": "The Decameron [or Il Decamerone]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A character in this novel releases fish from an underwater cage after a fisherman refuses to sell him any. That character, who is also called Black Whirlwind, later ends up fighting another character named White Stripe in the Waves. A version of this novel with 10 more chapters is called Chronicles of Heroes. A character in this novel is known for wielding twin axes, while another character drinks 18 bowls of wine at a time. A tiger is killed by a priest in one section of this novel, which became the basis for The (*) Plum in the Golden Vase. A group nicknamed the \u201cOriginal Seven\u201d rob birthday gifts for Cai Jing in this novel, whose characters are released after a stone tortoise is removed. For 10 points, name this classical Chinese novel about a group of 108 outlaws written by Shi Nai\u2019an.", "answer": "Water Margin [or Shui Hu Zhuan; also accept Outlaws of the Marsh, Tale of the Marshes, or All Men Are Brothers]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The title figures joyfully run \u201cdown a green plain\u201d in one poem by this author. The subjects that poem are \u201clocked up\u201d in \u201ccoffins of black\u201d but later \u201crise upon clouds.\u201d A poem by this author describes how a cry appalls \u201cEvery blackning Church\u201d and notes \u201cHow youthful Harlots curse\u201d in the title city. This author\u2019s most famous poem questions a \u201cdread (*) hand\u201d and \u201cdread feet\u201d and describes \u201cdistant deeps or skies.\u201d This author wrote about \u201clittle Tom Dacre\u201d who \u201ccould scarcely cry \u2018weep!\u2019\u201d in another poem. He asks \u201cWhat the anvil?\u201d and \u201cwho could frame thy fearful symmetry\u201d in his most famous poem. For 10 points, name this poet of \u201cThe Chimney Sweeper\u201d who wrote about an animal \u201cburning bright, in the forests of the night\u201d in \u201cThe Tyger.\u201d", "answer": "William Blake", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A work titled for one of these events says to \u201cpour away the ocean\u201d and mentions times such as \u201cmy noon\u201d and \u201cmy midnight.\u201d A poem titled for one of these events depicts \u201cBoots of lead creaking\u201d before metaphorically comparing \u201cBeing\u201d to \u201can Ear.\u201d A \u201cmuffled drum\u201d appears in a poem describing one of these events which also shows a dog barking at a \u201cjuicy bone.\u201d A later stanza of that poem begins, (*) \u201cHe was my North, my South, my East, and West.\u201d A poem depicting one of these events describes \u201csome strange race\u201d before claiming that a \u201cplank of reason\u201d broke. That poem depicting one of these events states that the speaker \u201chit a world at every plunge\u201d and thought her \u201cmind was going numb.\u201d For 10 points, name these solemn events, one of which Emily Dickinson felt \u201cin [her] Brain\u201d and another of which titles a W. H. Auden poem about its \u201cBlues.\u201d", "answer": "funeral [accept \u201cI Felt a Funeral in my Brain\u201d or \u201cFuneral Blues\u201d; do not accept or prompt on \u201cdeath\u201d]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this work runs into his political rival Farinta, and Ciacco foretells the political future of his home city. One character tells the narrator of this poem that a book about Lancelot and Guinevere caused her and her lover\u2019s downfall. The narrator of this poem passes out due to an earthquake, and it ends with the two protagonists (*) \u201c[coming] forth to rebehold the stars.\" A story about Ruggieri starving his sons is told by Count Ugolino to the protagonist of this poem, who earlier witnesses Minos wrapping his tail around himself. The narrator of this poem weeps at the story of Paolo and Francesca, and begins the poem \u201cmidway upon the journey of [his] life\u201d before being approached in a dark wood by a leopard, she-wolf, and lion. Virgil guides the poet in, for 10 points, what first part of Dante\u2019s Divine Comedy?", "answer": "Inferno [prompt on the Divine Comedy before mention]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A character created by this man is noted for his \u201cParthian volley of expletives.\u201d In the work in which that character appears, accordion music accompanies a man as he reads the Iliad aloud and mispronounces a Homeric character\u2019s name. The sailor Man O\u2019 War Jack sings a song about the Arethusa in one of this man\u2019s works, which also describes the improvement of local businesses such as Tuttle\u2019s Grocery. A work by this author features characters nicknamed \u201cThe (*) Innocent\u201d and \u201cThe Duchess\u201d who try to reach the Sandy Bar, while another of this author\u2019s stories features a character who allegedly had his finger \u201crastled\u201d by a baby. In that work, a flood of the North Fork River ravages citizens of the title town including the child of Cherokee Sal. For 10 points, name this author of \u201cThe Outcasts of Poker Flat\u201d and \u201cThe Luck of Roaring Camp.\u201d", "answer": "Bret Harte", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In a short story by this author, a character asks, \u201cDo you know anything about Madame Du Barry? didn\u2019t she have her head chopped off?\u201d to which another character responds, \u201cShe was another great lover of gardening.\u201d That story ends with Harvey Bope declaring \u201cthe experiment has failed. We have begun too late.\u201d This author wrote a different short story in which J.P. Huddle\u2019s addiction to routine is broken by a fake plot to massacre Jews invented by Clovis Sangrail. In a story by this author, a boy calls out, (*) \u201cBertie, why do you bound?\u201d That story ends with the line \u201cRomance at a short notice was her specialty\u201d after the protagonist, Framton Nuttel, bolts out of the house upon seeing three hunters through the title structure. For 10 points, name this British author of \u201cThe Toys of Peace,\u201d \u201cThe Unrest Cure,\u201d and \u201cThe Open Window.\u201d", "answer": "Saki [or Hector Hugh Munro; or H. H. Munro]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One character in this play helps take an insect out of another character\u2019s eye, leading them to reconcile and kiss. A group of characters in this play attempts to use earthen pots of fire to smoke out another group, only to have water dumped on their heads. A character repeatedly goes inside a building and retrieves items in this play, angering her husband Kinesias. Characters use the body of the naked handmaiden (*) Peace as a map of Greece near the end of this play, while it opens with Lampito and Calconice meeting with the title character and swearing an oath over a jug of wine. The protagonist of this play seizes the Acropolis in her plan to end a war. For 10 points, name this Aristophanes comedy in which women refuse to have sex with their husbands until the Peloponnesian War ends.", "answer": "Lysistrata", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One novel by this author centers on a professor of French history named John who switches places with a man who looks and sounds exactly like him. The protagonist of a short story by this author barricades him and his family in their house after he sees the corpse of his boss, Mr. Trigg, while looking for supplies. This author of The Scapegoat also wrote about a man who shot his first wife in the head a few months before she would have died of cancer. This author featured the war vet (*) Nat Hocken in a story in which the title animals kill all of his neighbors. This author\u2019s most famous work features an unnamed narrator whose marriage to Maxim de Winter is plagued by the housekeeper Mrs. Danvers. This author had one of her short stories adapted into the Hitchcock film The Birds. For 10 points, name this British novelist of Rebecca.", "answer": "Daphne du Maurier", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}], "bonuses": []}